# Daniel Pinedo

□+1 213-999-5619 | **Second Second Se** 

#### Introduction \_\_\_

I have extensive experience in higher education as a university lecturer, academic counselor, and organizational psychologist. I have MA degrees in Clinical Psychology and Organizational Behavior.

My work experiences have varied over the last 20 years from IT network administration and management, to most recent Global HR consulting and data science support for external program evaluators at the National Science Foundation. I delight in being a lifelong learner and strive to never stop learning.

Counseling and mentoring people to successfully complete their educational goals is both a strong skill set and passion that weaves throughout my varied professional experiences.

## Education \_\_

#### **Claremont Graduate University**

Claremont, CA

MA Psychology

Sep 2018 - May 2020

• Concentrations in Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

### **Sofia University**

Palo Alto, CA

MA Psychology

Sep 2010 - May 2013

Concentration in Clinical Psychology

#### **Naropa University**

Boulder, CO

**BA TRADITIONAL EASTERN ARTS** 

Sep 2008 - May 2010

• Student Government: Treasurer

## Professional Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Sep 2019 - Mar 2022	Principal, Kinesis Consulting (20 hours / week)
Nov 2018 - Jun 2020	Consultant, Accenture Plc, CGU Talent Innovation Lab (20 hours / week)
Sep 2016 - May 2018	Lecturer (and academic counselor), Psychology, Mount Saint Mary's University (full time)
Aug 2014 - Jul 2015	Clinician, Sovereign Health Group, adult partial inpatient rehabilitation center (full time)
Aug 2013 - Jul 2014	Clinician, Mind Body Awareness Project, adolescent drug and alcohol counseling (20 hours / week)
Aug 2012 - Jul 2013	Clinician, San Mateo County juvenile detention center, forensic psychological evaluation (20 hours / week)
Aug 2011 - Jul 2012	Clinician, Lifemoves family homeless shelter, individual & family therapy (20 hours / week)
2002 - 2008	IT Consultant, network engineering specialist (full time)

Teaching	& Counseling	
2017-2018	Academic Counseling, 10-15 students per semester	MSMU
SP 2018	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture, Lecturer	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab, Lecturer	
FA 2017	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture (Two Sections), Lecturer	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab (Two Sections), Lecturer	
SP 2017	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture, Adjunct	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab, Adjunct	
	Industrial & Organizational Psychology, Adjunct	
FA 2016	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture, Adjunct	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab, Adjunct	
	Social Psychology, Adjunct	
SP 2016	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lecture, Adjunct	
	Basic Quantitative Research Methods, Lab, Adjunct	
SP 2012	Doctoral Seminar: Qualitative Research, Teaching Assistant	Sofia
FA 2012	Special Topic: Dissertation Research and Writing Support, Teaching Assistant	

## **Evaluation**

Kinesis Consulting

Phoenixville, PA

ROLE: PRINCIPAL

Sep 2019 - Mar 2022

- Statistical consultation including social science methodology, visualization, and presentation in support of policy & planning
  analysis and program evaluation for the scientific community. Focus is on methodological innovation for evaluation in support
  of climate change mitigation and resilience infrastructure projects. Examples of recent projects:
  - Survey analysis and presentation for external program evaluation in NSF Directorate for Geosciences
  - Mixed method / Social network analysis for external program evaluation in NSF Division of Undergraduate Education
  - Social network analyses for external program evaluation in NSF Office of Integrative Activities.

#### Research -

ADVISOR: DR. FRED LUSKIN

#### **Sofia University - Dept of Clinical Psychology**

Palo Alto, CA

Sept. 2010 - March 2013

- Training: Core & Advanced dense array EEG Certification; EGI, Eugene, OR
- Manager: Electroencephalography Lab
- Internship: Editing & Peer Review, International Journal of Transpersonal Studies
- Research: the self-reported experience; and, perceived changes in self-compassion, emotion regulation, and psychological-mindedness of college-bound and college matriculated, STEM mentoring program Latino youth participants after a mindfulness and compassion meditation retreat

#### Publications \_\_

#### **PUBLISHED**

Himelstein, S., Saul, S., Garcia-Romeu, A., & **Pinedo, D.** (2014). Mindfulness training as an intervention for substance user incarcerated adolescents: A pilot grounded theory study. *Substance Use & Misuse*.

Kaczmarczyk, L., & **Pinedo, D.** (2021). Getting things done in data intensive inter-campus research initiatives: A social network analysis approach to understanding and building effective relationships between researchers and other university employees. In *Proceedings of the 2021 American Society for Engineering Education Annual Conference & Exposition* (Vol. 26)

## Presentations \_\_\_

#### INVITED TALKS

Spring 2018, Fall 2017. <sup>†</sup> Coordination of symposium and opening speech on topic of importance of promoting undergraduate research and representation of women in STEM. Invited talk: Undergraduate research symposium, Mount Saint Mary's University, Los Angeles, CA

<sup>&</sup>lt;sup>+</sup> mentored undergraduates

#### **CONTRIBUTED PRESENTATIONS**

- Himelstein, S., & **Pinedo, D.** (2013). Empowering communities: An intensive mindfulness training in a retreat setting for college-bound adolescents and college-aged tutors. [Meditation Retreat]. Redwood Glen Summer Camp; Loma Mar, CA.
- Himelstein, S., **Pinedo, D.**, & Mousseau, A. (2013). *Mindfulness training for educators: An intensive training at the Lakota Nation at Pine Ridge.* [Inservice Training]. Little Wound High School; Kyle, SD.
- Kaczmarczyk, L., & **Pinedo, D.** (July 2021). *Getting things done in data intensive inter-campus research initiatives: A social network analysis approach to understanding and building effective relationships between researchers and other university employees.* [Poster Presentation]. The 2021 American Society for Engineering Education Annual Conference & Exposition. Long Beach, CA.
- **Pinedo, D.**, Gutierrez, G., & Tinoco, C. (2013). Assessment, prevention, and discussion of health disparities in local Native American populations [Continuing Education Training]. Health Services Building, San Mateo, CA.

Awards, I	Fellowships, & Grants	
2018	Graduate Fellowship, Claremont Graduate University	\$ 20,000
2008	President's Scholarship, Naropa University	\$ 10,000
Mentorin	g Karina Garcia MSN RN CNL, Teaching Assistant, Mount Saint Mary's University	
Service &	Outreach	
2016	Wilshire Detective Division, Volunteer	LAPD
2014	Venice Neighborhood Council, Member, Neighborhood Committee	CA
2009	Student Government, Treasurer	Naropa